(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-24T01:45:01.788554",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
ホロライブサマー２０２２…、最後のフィナーレはライブの開催です！
Hololive Summer 2022... The final finale is a live performance!
この夏は 何度も 夢見た渚の宝物
This summer, the treasure of the shore I dreamed of time and again,
Shiny Smile
Smile Your Heart
Heart to Heart
Oh Yeah
（せーのっ）ぴえん ぱおん はにゃん お待たせっ♡
(Ready, go!) Pien, paon, hanyan, thanks for waiting♡
さーまさまさまさま あっちっちーの「さまー」
Sumasumasumasu, sizzling hot "Summer"!
さーまさまさまさま ぴっちぴち「さまー」
Sumasumasumasu, bouncy-bouncy "Summer"!
いーけいけ「さまー」 いーちゃいちゃ「さまー」
Go, go, "Summer", get cozy, "Summer"!
女神さま fooo~~~~~~~！！
Goddess-sama, foooo~~~~~~~!!
（A！）ええ塩梅の空に白い雲 そして
(A!) White clouds in the nice salty breeze, and
（B！）ビーチ砂浜これこのムード
(B!) Sandy beach, this, this mood,
（素晴らC！）史上最強の私がヴィーナス
(Wonderful C!) The strongest in history, I'm the Venus.
一番なんて決めらんない
I can't decide just who's number one,
「それな？」
"Right?"
（D！）どこで買ったの水着？ めっちゃE！
(D!) Where'd you buy that swimsuit? So E!
「いいですね～」「いいですね～」
"Nice!" "Nice!"
煩悩お空へ飛んでっK！（飛んでっK！）
Fly your worldly desires to the sky! (Fly to K!)
経験豊富な私たちでも 至らない境地 それがホロライブサマー！
A realm we haven't reached—that's Hololive Summer!
パラソルにチェア この時間フォーエバー
Parasols and chairs, this time is forever.
キミも隣り来る？ （キタ キタ キタ キタ）
Wanna come sit next to me? (Here it comes!)
ビーチの1級建築士（Uh！） 波打ち際にキャスト新築（Ha！）
The beach's first-class architect (Uh!), casting a new castle by the waves (Ha!)
もっと はしゃぎ過ぎたくって
Wanting to play and party even more,
「その目に焼き付けろおおおおお！！！！」
"Burn it into your eyes, ooooooh!!!!"
（イェ~~~~~~~イ）
(Yeah~~~~~~~!)
この夏は（ハイ！） 何度も（ハイ！） 夢見た渚の宝物
This summer (High!), time and again (High!), the treasure of the shore I dreamed of
Shiny smile（う～Shiny smile）
Shiny Smile (Ooh~ Shiny Smile)
飛沫あけて（ハイ！） 弾けて（ハイ！） また笑って（ヤｰ！）
Shedding spray (High!), bursting (High!), laughing again (Yeah!)
裸足で描いてる Story
Drawing a story barefoot.
泳いで（Fufu） 泳いで（Fufu） その先へ
Swimming (Fufu), swimming (Fufu), towards beyond that.
（せーのっ）ぴえん ぱおん はにゃん はぴはぴっ♡
(Ready, go!) Pien, paon, hanyan, happy happy♡
さーまさまさまさま あっちっちーの「さまー」
Sumasumasumasu, sizzling hot "Summer"!
さーまさまさまさま ぴっちぴち「さまー」
Sumasumasumasu, bouncy-bouncy "Summer"!
いーけいけ「さまー」 いーちゃいちゃ「さまー」
Go, go, "Summer", get cozy, "Summer"!
女神さま fooo~~~~~~~！！
Goddess-sama, foooo~~~~~~~!!
（ワン！）水着の柄を褒めるべし～
(One!) Praise the pattern of the swimsuit~
（ツー！）海の魔物から守るべし～
(Two!) Protect from the monsters of the sea~
（スリー！）他の娘は見ちゃヤダヤダヤダ～（ヤダヤダヤダ～）
(Three!) Looking at other girls is no-no-no~ (No-no-no~)
一番だって言ってよね（よっしゃー）
Say I'm number one, okay? (All right!)
汗ばむ肌と（肌と） ギラギラサンセット（サンセット）
Sweaty skin and (skin and) glittering sunset (sunset)
お待たせねボンファイアー！（キタ キタ キタ キタ）
Thanks for waiting, bonfires! (Here it comes!)
パーティー開催午後六時（午後六時） ドレスコードは日焼けのアート（日焼けのアート）
Party starts at 6 PM (6 PM), dress code is a suntanned art (suntanned art)
空に 花火打ち上がって
Fireworks shooting up into the sky,
「パーティーの始まりだあああああ！！！！」
"The party is starting ooooooh!!!!"
（カンパ~~~~~イ！）
(Cheers~~~~~!)
この夏も（ハイ！） いつかは（ハイ！） キラめく思い出になるよね
This summer too (High!), someday (High!), will become a sparkling memory, right?
Shooting Star（う～Shooting Star）
Shooting Star (Ooh~ Shooting Star)
声をあげて（ハイ！） 願えば（ハイ！） ほら叶うよ（ヤｰ！）
Raise your voice (High!), if you wish (High!), look, it comes true (Yeah!)
神様だって見惚れちゃう
Even the gods will be captivated.
たわわで（Fufu） はわわな（Fufu） パラダイス
Plump (Fufu), fluttery (Fufu) paradise.
（せーのっ）ぴえん ぱおん はにゃん どきどきっ♡
(Ready, go!) Pien, paon, hanyan, dokidoki♡
これこそが！YES！ホロライブサマー！！（ホロライブサマー！！）
This is it! YES! Hololive Summer!! (Hololive Summer!!)
最高の景色 そして じゃわわなヴィーナス
The best scenery, and a fluttery Venus,
骨の髄まで遊び尽くせーーー！！
Enjoy it to the boneーーー!!
ビーチバレー！いくわよー！オルラージェストオォー
Beach volleyball! Here we go! Oh-rye gestooo!
浜メシ 爆メシ 限りなし 惜しぃ！
Beach food, explosive food, endless, what a shame!
ジェットスキーでバナナボートにキック！
Kick the banana boat with a jet ski!
負けたらチョメチョメ 王様ゲーム！？
Lose and it's chome-chome King game!?
のぞいちゃダメ
No peeking!
岩場の陰でお着替え（あんっ）
Changing clothes in the shade of the rocks (An~)
乙女の秘密は ハラドキ×4
A maiden's secret is heart-thumping x4
いやぁ~~~~~~~ん
No way~~~~~~~!
黄昏の浜辺で 背中合わせた合言葉は
On the twilight beach, the password we shared back-to-back is
I Need You (I Need You)
波の音が 痺れさせる
The sound of waves makes me tingle
火照った身体
My heated body...
ドキドキ もう止まんないね
My heart won't stop pounding anymore!
真夏の奇跡 (真夏の奇跡)
A midsummer miracle (A midsummer miracle)
ちゅわちゅわちゅわちゅわちゅわちゅわちゅわ～
Chuwa chuwa chuwa...
この声も (ハイ！) 想いも (ハイ！)
This voice too (Hey!), these feelings too (Hey!)
夢見た渚の宝物 Shiny Smile (う~Shiny Smile)
Treasure of the dreamed shore, Shiny Smile (~Shiny Smile)
時を止めて (ハイ！) みんなで (ハイ！) また笑って (ヤー！)
Stop time (Hey!), everyone together (Hey!), laughing again (Yay!)
裸足で描いた ハートマーク
A heart mark drawn barefoot
歌って (FuFu) 遊んで (FuFu) その先へ
Singing (FuFu), playing (FuFu), going beyond
ぴえん ぱおん ぴょん さまさま♡
Pien, paon, pyon, all sorts♡
「最高の夏にしようねっ♪」
"Let's make it the best summer♪"
この海で
In this sea...
生まれたてのドキドキを響かせよう
Let's make our newborn heartbeats echo
最高の時間 最高の仲間と キラメキノオト
With the best time and best friends, a sparkling sound
キラメキラライダー☆
Kirameki Rider☆
覚えてるかな 最初道の歌 懐かしいね
Do you remember our very first song? So nostalgic
私の声が震えていたほんの少し
My voice was trembling, just a little bit
あの日から続く未来はみんなと掴んだそうだよ
The future continuing from that day, we grasped together
もっともっともっともっと加速するハート一緒にいくよどこまでも
Accelerating our hearts more and more, let's go anywhere together!
準備は OK?
Are you ready? Preparation's OK?
開け夢の扉を 1・2・3 キラメキラライダー☆
Open the door to our dreams! 1, 2, 3, Kirameki Rider☆
生まれたてのドキドキを響かせよう
Let's make our newborn heartbeats echo
最高の時間 最高の仲間と
With the best time and best friends
ここにいるよ 見つけてくれたから
I'm right here, because you found me
君に会いたくてやってきたんだ みんなで歌おう
I came here wanting to see you, let's all sing together
終わらないメロディ キラメキノオト
A never-ending melody, a sparkling sound
キラメキラライダー☆
Kirameki Rider☆
届いてるかな 私の声 はっきりと
I wonder if my voice is reaching you clearly
届けたいのは 君に笑顔 その笑顔
What I want to deliver to you is a smile, that smile
一歩一歩の遠さにくやしくて
Frustrated by the distance of step by step
みんなと泣き笑ったね
We cried and laughed together
ぎゅっぎゅっぎゅっとキュートすべて抱きしめて
Hugging tight, cute, holding everything close
一緒にいこうどこまでも 準備は OK?
Let's go anywhere together! Are you ready?
進め希望の道を 1・2・3 キラメキラライダー☆
Advance on the path of hope! 1, 2, 3, Kirameki Rider☆
好きの気持ちからフルニ声奏でたいな
I want to make my voice resound from my feelings of love
最高の場合 最高のみんなと
In the best place, with everyone at our best
ここにいるよ 幻なんかじゃない
I'm right here, this is no illusion
君の心が幸せに染まるよ
Your heart will be dyed in happiness
重ねてくハーモニー キラメキノオト
Layering harmonies, a sparkling sound
歌い続けたいな 踊り続けたいな
I want to keep singing, I want to keep dancing
そんな願いやわがままでもいいでしょ
Such wishes and selfishness are fine, right?
だって楽しすぎてもっともっともっと
Because it's too much fun, more and more and more!
輝くステージでもっともっと お願い！
On the shining stage, even more! Please!
ずっと！ オー！ イェー！
Forever! Oh! Yeah!
嬉しい 楽しい 愛しいだけじゃ語れない
Happy, fun, beloved—words alone aren't enough
今も今も悩みはあるけど
Even now, even now, there are worries, but...
生まれたてのドキドキを響かせよう
Let's make our newborn excitement resonate!
最高の時間 最高の仲間と
With the best time and the best friends,
キラメキに載って☆
Riding on the sparkle☆
(イエーイ!)
(Yeah!)
覚えてるかな? 最初の歌 (懐かしいね)
Do you remember? Our first song (So nostalgic)
私 声が震えていた (ほんの少し)
My voice was trembling (Just a little)
あの日から続く 未来は
The future continuing from that day
みんなで掴んだ今日だよ
Is today that we grasped together with everyone
もっともっともっともっと 加速するハート (一緒に)
Faster and faster, accelerating heart (Together)
行くよ どこまでも (are you ready?)
Let's go anywhere (Are you ready?)
準備はOK?
Is everything ready?
ひらけ!! 夢のトビラを (一、二、三)
Open!! The door of dreams (One, two, three)
(キラメキ ライダー☆)
(Kirameki Rider☆)
生まれたてのドキドキを響かせよう
Let's make our newborn excitement resonate,
最高の時間 最高の仲間と
with the best time and the best friends,
ここにいるよ 見つけてくれたから
I'm right here, because you found me,
君に会いたくて みんなで歌おう
Wanting to see you, let's sing together!
届けてるかな? 私の声 (ハッキリと)
Is my voice reaching you? (Clearly)
届けたいのは 君に笑顔 (そのスマイル!)
What I want to deliver is your smile
理想の遠さに 悔しくて
Frustrated by the distance of ideals,
みんなで泣き笑ったね
We cried and laughed together, didn't we?
ぎゅっと ぎゅっと 全て 抱きしめて (一緒に)
Hold everything tight, tight, tight (Together)
はい、ということで！はーい、こんばんはー！こんばんはー！
Hi, so—! Hi, good evening! Good evening!
本日は、ホロライブサマー2022の最後を飾るライブ、クライマックスストーリーライブを観に来てくれてみんな、ありがとー！
Thank you everyone for coming to see the climax live today!
ありがとー！いえーい！
Thank you! Yay!
公式チャンネルでやるライブということでね、僕たちのことを知らない人もいると思うから、最初に自己紹介しておきましょうか。
Let's do self-introductions first for those who might not know us.
おっけー！あけまめ！じゃあ僕からいきますね。
Okay! Well, I'll go first.
いくよ、もぐもぐおかゆー！ホロライブゲーマーズの猫又おかゆです！
Here I go, Mogu Mogu Okayu! I'm Nekomata Okayu from Hololive Gamers!
今日はめいいっぱい楽しんでくださいね！いえーい！
Please enjoy yourselves to the fullest today! Yay!
はい！はろーぼー！えっと、いややこうせいのバーチャルロボットのロボ子だよー！みんな楽しんどるかー？楽しんどるよなー！おーい！
Hi! I'm Roboco, the virtual robot! Are you all having fun?
はい、みなさんこんばんは！ホロライブ3期生のノーキィ、白銀ノエルでーす！いや今日はめちゃめちゃ楽しむぞー！いえーい！
Hi everyone, good evening! I'm Noel Shirogane from Hololive 3rd Gen!
はい、ということで私たち3人がキラメキラライダーをお届けしましたー！お届けしましたー！私たちこの3人はね、ふわふわっとした感じのキラメキラライダーになったんじゃないでしょうか？
So the three of us delivered Kirameki Rider! Wasn't it fluffy?
1曲目もね、みなさん見ましたか？いや、見た！もうなんか元気だった！元気だったよね！元気だった！
Did you all watch the first song too? It was so energetic!
新曲のとんでけホロライブサマーは、ライブ初公開ということで、最初から飛ばしてたねー！なんか、ABCでめちゃめちゃやってて、めちゃめちゃ可愛かった！
The new song was premiered live, so we were going all out!
あ、ちょっと待って！何？先輩？どうしたの？いや、ちょっと忘れていること…みんなも忘れてない？ちゃんと、何なに？ホロライブサマーと言ったら、水着！ですよ！
Ah, wait! Speaking of Hololive Summer, it's swimwear!
水着！水着でダンスするのは、公式では今回初公開なんだ！おー！すごいね！
Dancing in swimwear is a first for the official channel!
じゃあ、せっかくだしね、着てる人のこの僕たちの姿をね、みんなにも見てもらいますか？
Shall we show everyone our appearance wearing it?
じゃあちょっと一緒にピースなんかしてましょっか。あ、ピース！あ、ちょっとペコペコ、アイドルっぽい！アイドルっぽいよね！はい、チーズ！いぇーい！かわいいー！
Let's strike a cute pose. Say cheese! Yay! So cute!
えー、ちょっと近づいちゃったりして。ねえ、みんなスクショット撮ってさ、思い出にツイートしてね！みんな撮っとるかー？かわいいー！かわいいー！
Take a screenshot and tweet it as a memory! Cute!
じゃあ、さてみなさん、満足してくれたかな？くれたかな？くれてたかしら？そろそろね、次の曲に行かないとなんですけど、最後にみんなはホロライブサマーのストーリーは追ってくれたのかな？
Did everyone follow the story of Hololive Summer?
あ、そうだね、ストーリーがありました！まだ追ってない人はもうこのライブが終わった後にピャーッと追ってください！
For those who haven't yet, please catch up right after this!
もう追いつけるからね、ぜひぜひチェックしてくれよな！よーチェック！
You can still catch up, so definitely check it out!
ということでね、そろそろ時間もきたので、次の曲いってみましょうか！オーケーもらう！キラマックスストーリーライブはまだまだ続くので、みなさんぜひ最後まで見てくださいね！
The Climax Story Live continues, so please watch until the end!
お願いしまーす！おねがいしまーす！続いての曲は？こちらでーす！
Please! What is the next song? Here it is!
少しずつ近づいているよ 夢見たトキメキ
We are getting a little closer to the excitement we dreamed of
少しずつ近づいているよ
A little bit closer now,
夢にみたトキメキ
the excitement I dreamed of.
広がっていく世界中に
Spreading across the world,
皆を笑顔にするキラメキを
a sparkle to make everyone smile.
一人じゃないから ライバルがいるから
Because I'm not alone, because I have rivals,
競い合うことすら 楽しくなれちゃうんだよ
even competing becomes so much fun!
dear my friends
未来へ走り出したら fantastic
if we start running toward the future, fantastic,
夢を咲かせて our future
let our dreams bloom, our future.
一歩一歩を踏み出して トップを目指そう
Taking step by step, let's aim for the top!
信じる力が 心のhappiness 全力で楽しもう
The power to believe is heart's happiness, let's enjoy it fully!
それはいつかきっと
That will surely someday...
大きな夢 叶えるから
Fulfill our big dream!
dreaming days
答えのない道を行く 誰も見たことのない世界
Going down a path with no answers, a world nobody has seen,
連れて行くよ 皆の事 覚悟は良いかな？ 手を離さないで
I'll take everyone with me. Are you ready? Don't let go of my hand.
一人じゃないから 君が見ているから
Because I'm not alone, because you're watching,
初めての挑戦すら 楽しくなれちゃうんだよ
even our first challenge becomes so much fun!
daydream believe
yeah!!
奇跡を巻き起こすんだ glorious 夢に近づいて my story
Stirring up miracles, glorious, getting closer to my dream, my story.
とても小さな蕾が 花咲かせるまで
Until a very small bud blooms into a flower,
挑戦し続けるんだ brilliant 全力で飛び込もう
I will keep challenging, brilliant, let's dive in with all our might!
ほんの少しだけの 勇気が今をくれたんだ
Just a tiny bit of courage gave us the present moment.
dreaming days
選んできた未来の選択肢 全てがほら 私を作った
The choices of the future I've chosen, look, they all made me.
選ぶことのなかった過去さえ 大事な意味があったと気づいたよ
Even the pasts I didn't choose had important meanings, I realized.
涙を流した数が emotion 熱い心が over heat
The tears I shed are emotion, my burning heart is over heat.
本気だからこそ 思える トップになりたい！
Because I'm dead serious, I feel it—I want to be on top!
未来へ走り出したら fantastic
If we start running toward the future, fantastic,
全力で楽しもう
let's enjoy it with all our might!
それはいつかきっと
That will surely someday...
大きな夢 叶えるから
Fulfill our big dream!
dreaming days
oh yeah
走り続けていくんだ grateful 一人じゃ届かない高みへ
I'll keep running, grateful, to heights I could never reach alone!
yeah!!
奇跡を巻き起こすんだ glorious 夢に近づいて my story
Stirring up miracles, glorious, getting closer to my dream, my story.
とても小さな蕾が 花咲かせるまで
Until a very small bud blooms into a flower,
挑戦し続けるんだ brilliant 全力で飛び込もう
I will keep challenging, brilliant, let's dive in with all our might!
ほんの少しだけの 勇気が今をくれたんだ
Just a tiny bit of courage gave us the present moment.
dreaming days
ほんの少しだけの 勇気が今をくれたんだ
Just a tiny bit of courage gave us the present moment.
dreaming days
選んできた未来の選択肢 全てがほら 私を作った
The choices of the future I've chosen, look, they all made me.
選ぶことのなかった過去さえ 大事な意味があったと気づいたよ
Even the pasts I didn't choose had important meanings, I realized.
涙を流した数が emotion 熱い心が over heat
The tears I shed are emotion, my burning heart is over heat.
本気だからこそ 思える トップになりたい！
Because I'm dead serious, I feel it—I want to be on top!
未来へ走り出したら fantastic 全力で楽しもう
If we start running toward the future, fantastic, let's enjoy it fully!
それはいつかきっと 大きな夢 叶えるから
That will surely someday fulfill our big dream!
dreaming days
oh yeah
走り続けていくんだ grateful 一人じゃ届かない高みへ
I'll keep running, grateful, to heights I could never reach alone!
yeah!!
本気だからこそ 思える トップになりたい！
Because I'm dead serious, I feel it—I want to be on top!
未来へ走り出したら fantastic
If we start running toward the future, fantastic,
全力で楽しもう
let's enjoy it with all our might!
それはいつかきっと
That will surely someday...
大きな夢 叶えるから
Fulfill our big dream!
dreaming days
oh yeah
走り続けていくんだ grateful 一人じゃ届かない高みへ
I'll keep running, grateful, to heights I could never reach alone!
yeah!!
未来へ走り出したら fantastic
If we start running toward the future, fantastic,
全力で楽しもう
let's enjoy it with all our might!
それはいつかきっと
That will surely someday...
大きな夢 叶えるから
Fulfill our big dream!
走り続けていくんだ grateful 一人じゃ届かない高みへ
I'll keep running, grateful, to heights I could never reach alone!
yeah!!
手を上げて Clap your hands 空の向こうまで
Raise your hands, clap your hands, up to the other side of the sky!
Clap your hands 届きますように
Clap your hands, may it reach you!
手を叩こう 手を叩こう
Let's clap our hands, let's clap our hands!
ほら一緒に Everybody!
Look, everyone together, everybody!
Clap your hands 空の向こうまで
Clap your hands, up to the other side of the sky!
Clap your hands 響きますように
Clap your hands, may it resonate!
手を叩こう 手を叩こう
Let's clap our hands, let's clap our hands!
光り出す 僕たちの未来
Our shining future!
始めようか がっつり
Let's start full-throttle,
混ぜるの意味ないタイミング
in timing where mixing has no meaning.
あの魚みたいに スイミング スイミング
Swimming like that fish, swimming, swimming,
引き寄せるの ライティング
drawing in the lighting.
まだ見えない ドリーミング
Dreaming not yet seen,
この先には何があるの？
what lies ahead of us?
手を上げて
Raise your hands.
clap your hands 海の向こうまで
Clap your hands across the sea,
clap your hands 届くように
May it reach you,
手を叩こう 手を叩こう
Let's clap our hands, let's clap our hands!
ほら 一緒に everybody
C'mon now, together, everybody!
clap your hands 空の向こうまで
Clap your hands across the sky,
clap your hands 響きますように
May the claps resound,
手を叩こう 手を叩こう
Let's clap our hands, let's clap our hands!
光射す ぼくたちの未来
Light illuminates our future.
5 4 3 2 1
始めようか さあ diving
Shall we start? C'mon, diving!
待ってても意味ない timing
There's no use waiting, it's not a matter of timing.
あの魚みたいに swimming swimming
Like those fish, swimming, swimming!
呼び寄せるのさ lighting
The lighting calls us,
まだ見えないよ maybe
Maybe you still can't see it yet.
この先には何があるの？
What lies ahead of us?
まだ早いよ take it
It's still early, so take it!
追い付くまで shaking
Shaking until we catch up!
でもたまに止まってさ thinking thinking
But sometimes, stop and think, think!
変えてみせるさ change
We'll show you change,
踏み出すのさ stepping
Taking a step forward!
掴んでみせるよ キラキラ my dream
I'll grasp my sparkling dream!
叶う日まで story 繋ぐから
Connecting the story until the day it comes true,
だって君にずっと見ていてほしいから
Because I want you to watch me always!
手を上げて
Raise your hands.
clap your hands 海の向こうまで
Clap your hands across the sea,
clap your hands 届くように
May it reach you,
手を叩こう 手を叩こう
Let's clap, let's clap!
ほら 一緒に everybody
C'mon, together, everybody!
clap your hands 空の向こうまで
Clap your hands across the sky,
clap your hands 響きますように
May the claps resound,
手を叩こう 手を叩こう
Let's clap, let's clap!
光射す ぼくたちの未来
Light illuminates our future.
今日はいらないブレーキ
Today we don't need brakes,
理性壊せ breaking
Breaking our reason!
何時でもいいでしょ 四六時中
Anytime is fine, around the clock,
君は何を feeling？
What are you feeling?
解き放て sparking
Unleash the sparking!
暗闇に放つ レーザービーム
Laser beams unleashed into the darkness,
光らせて stage 作るから
Making the stage shine and build it,
だって君にもっと見ていてほしいから
Because I want you to watch me even more!
重なる wave 世界を揺らせ
Overlapping waves, shake the world!
終わりがある事くらい既にI know
I already know that everything has an end,
でもまだまだ泳ぎ足りないの
But I still haven't had enough of swimming!
（Boom！！！）give me crazy
Give me crazy,
（Boom！！！）まるでlazy？
Feeling like lazy?
（Boom！！！）次元混ざり合うの
Dimensions blending together,
全て塗り替える blue
Repainting everything blue!
手を上げて
Raise your hands.
clap your hands 海の向こうまで
Clap your hands across the sea,
clap your hands 届くように
May it reach you,
手を叩こう 手を叩こう
Let's clap, let's clap!
ほら 一緒に everybody
C'mon, together, everybody!
clap your hands 空の向こうまで
Clap your hands across the sky,
clap your hands 響きますように
May the claps resound,
手を叩こう 手を叩こう
Let's clap, let's clap!
光射す ぼくたちの未来
Light illuminates our future.
はーい、ということで！
Hiii, so yeah!
改めまして、BLUE CLAPPERをお届けしましたー！
Once again, we delivered BLUE CLAPPER!
いやー、ホロサマライブ2022、みんな楽しんでるかー！？
Man, is everyone enjoying HoloSummer Live 2022!?
楽しんでるかー！？
Enjoying it?!
音声も続いてる、続いてる。
The audio is keeping up, keeping up.
はい、ポルポルチャンネルということでね、簡単に自己紹介していきましょう！
Yes, as PolPol Channel, let's do a quick self-introduction!
はい、ネポラボのね、からいきましょう。
Let's start with NePoLaBo.
はーい、ネポラボのね、えー、桃鈴ねねでーす！
Hii, I'm Momosuzu Nene of NePoLaBo!
イェーイ！次、ねねち組まーす！
Yay! Next, Nenechi-gumi!
はい、ネポラボのポル、尾丸ポルカです！よろしくお願いします！
Yes, Pol of NePoLaBo, Omaru Polka! Nice to meet you!
イェーイ！そして？
Yay! And then?
次は？はーい、ネポラボのラミィ、雪花ラミィです！よろしくお願いします！
Next? Hii, Lamy of NePoLaBo, Yukihana Lamy! Nice to meet you!
そして、そして？
And, and?
はい、ネポラボのボ、獅白ぼたんです！よろしくお願いします！
Yes, Bo of NePoLaBo, Shishiro Botan! Nice to meet you!
はい、ということで、私たちでBLUE CLAPPERをお届けしましたー！
So yeah, we delivered BLUE CLAPPER!
どうだった？これは絶対盛り上がるよね、盛り上がるよ！
How was it? This definitely gets people hyped, right!
だって盛り上がらなかったことはない、盛り上がらない！これを私たちが歌って盛り上がらないわけがない！
It couldn't possibly not get hyped when we sing it!
あでも、その前に、えっと、うちらがね、歌った前にドリーミングデイズ組がね歌ってたじゃん！
Oh, but before that, you know, Dreamin' Days group sang before us!
よかったよねー！かわいいよね！あのチョコ先がちょっと先生だからさ本当に！
It was so good! So cute! Since Choco-sensei is a bit of a teacher, seriously!
なんか練習の時もさ、先生がさこうやって教えてくれてた！
Even during practice, sensei taught us like this!
可愛いかったわ。
It was cute.
ダンスも可愛かったしね。
And the dancing was cute, too.
振付けがさ、可愛かった！
The choreography was so cute!
ちょこちょこした動きがさ、身長低い組とスレンダーなちょこ先だと全然違う！
Those little scuttling movements are totally different between the short height group and slender Choco-sensei!
でもシオン先輩キレッキレ好き
But Shion-senpai's crisp dancing is great.
ゲーマーズだとこれね
For Gamers, it's like this.
すごかった！
That was amazing!
あ、アピールタイムす！
Ah, it's appeal time!
1番目紹介、上手いね！
Introducing number one, you're good!
うまいね！
That's so good!
ホロライブ・サマー2022グッズ、販売開始！
Hololive Summer 2022 merchandise goes on sale!
なんと今日から受注販売開始！
Orders open starting today!
3Dアクリルスタンド、そしてランダム缶バッジ、プレミアムアクリルパネル！
3D Acrylic Stands, random button badges, and premium acrylic panels!
こちらの新商品があるということです！
These new merchandise items are available!
3Dアクリルスタンド、シャニーウェーブ ver.
3D Acrylic Stand - Shiny Wave Ver.
アクリルスタンドは、あの、なんと35種類あるんでね！
The acrylic stands come in 35 different varieties!
ランダム缶バッジ、シャニーウェーブ ver.
Random Button Badge - Shiny Wave Ver.
こちらも35種類あるということで！
These also come in 35 varieties!
プレミアムアクリルパネル！
Premium Acrylic Panel!
こちらはですね、全員集合しているプレミアムアクリルパネルなんですけれども、
This is the premium acrylic panel featuring everyone together,
こちらのみ、本日からの9月14日までの受注生産となっておりますので、
and this item only is available for order from today until September 14th,
ぜひこのタイミングで手に入れてください！
so please make sure to get yours at this timing!
詳細は概要欄にあるホロライブプロダクションオフィシャルショップをチェックしてください！
Please check the Hololive Production official shop link in the description for details!
重ねた手はギュッと離さずに
Without letting go of our intertwined hands tightly,
行くよ行こう 夢見る空へ
Let's go, let's go to the sky of our dreams.
まだ星に見上げた とっても小さな空
Looking up at the stars in a still very small sky,
ここで出会えたのは 数え切れない奇跡
meeting here was an uncountable miracle.
繰り返した一歩が きらめきを繋いで
Repeated steps connected the sparkling light,
星のような笑顔の水色糸
A light-blue thread of smiles like stars.
Day by day みんなの声が力になる
Day by day, everyone's voice becomes my strength.
Step by step ここでそれぞれ描く未来
Step by step, the future each of us draws here,
それぞれ描くカタチの、それぞれ描く片夢へ
each drawing our own form, toward the dream each of us envisions.
重ねた手は ギュッと 離さずに(行こう！)
Keep your hands tightly together, go!
夢見る空へ
To the dreaming sky!
窓越しに見上げた とても小さな空
Looking up through the window, a very small sky.
ここで出逢えたのは 数え切れないキセキ
I met countless miracles here.
繰り返した一歩が キラメキをつないで
Repeated steps connect the glitter,
星のような笑顔導いた
Guided by a smile like a star.
day by day みんなの 声 が チカラ に なる
Day by day, everyone's voice becomes power.
stage by stage ここ で それぞれ 目指す もの
Stage by stage, each aims for what they seek,
それぞれ 描く もの それぞれ 願っ た 夢 へ
Drawing what each wants, toward each dreamed-of sky.
重ねた手は ギュッと 離さずに
Keep your hands tightly together without letting go,
ひとり(ひとり) 違う(色で) 描き出すトキメキ
Drawing excitement with different colors, one by one.
振り向く こと なく まっすぐ に
Going straight ahead without ever looking back,
行く よ ！ (行こう！) 夢見る 空 へ
Go! (Let's go!) To the dreaming sky.
笑い合ったことや 尽きそうない話題
Laughter and endless topics,
思い出いっぱいなのに あっという間の日々
Memories filling each day in the blink of an eye.
上書きじゃなくて 名前つけて保存
Naming and saving them instead of overwriting,
どれも 全部 大切って言い切れる
I can say that every single one is precious.
one for all “みんなのため” が チカラ に なる
One for all, "for everyone" becomes power.
all for all 今日 も にぎやか すぎる くらい
All for all, today is too lively,
笑顔が もう 止まらない 想いは ふくらんでいく
Smiles won't stop as feelings swell up.
重ねた 今 ギュッと かみしめた
Holding this present moment tight,
ひとり(ひとり) 違う(声で) 歌声は広がる
Singing voices spread with different voices.
風を 感じたら まっすぐ に
Feeling the wind, go straight ahead,
行く よ ！ (行こう！) 夢見る 空 へ
Go! (Let's go!) To the dreaming sky.
“憧れ”へ 手を伸ばし つかみとったその光が
Reaching for longing, the light I grabbed,
いつの日か また 誰かの“憧れ”に変わる つなげよう
Someday turns into someone else's longing. Let's connect it!
重ねた手は ギュッと 離さずに
Keep your hands tightly together without letting go,
ひとり(ひとり) 違う(色で) 描き出すトキメキ
Drawing excitement with different colors, one by one.
出逢った 全てに ありがとう
Thank you for everything we've met.
キセキ(だって) 起こし(続け)
May miracles keep waking up,
ずっと(ずっと) そばにいるよ
I'll be by your side forever.
行く よ ！ (行こう！) 夢見る 空 へ
Go! (Let's go!) To the dreaming sky.
いつの間にか見つけていた遠い夢
A distant dream I found before I knew it,
一人じゃ見えなかった景色
Scenery that could not be seen alone.
波打つ風の音と 加速していく想いに
The sound of rippling wind and accelerating feelings
戸惑いを覚えた
Made me feel confused.
ずっと追いかけた理想の姿は
The ideal figure I chased all the time
まだ届かなくて遠いけど
Still isn't reached, but distant.
きっとこの瞬間を かけがえないみんなで
I'm sure this moment is irreplaceable with everyone.
共に 行く よ ！ 手 を 繋い で
Let's go together! Holding hands,
3 . 2 . 1 ！ 輝き 宿して 夢 の 場所 へ ！
3, 2, 1! Let radiance dwell and head to the place of dreams!
駆け抜けていく 僕たちの 青春 の 光 は
The light of our youth running through
誰 に も 止められない よ ！
No one can stop it!
笑い合う分だけ優しく
Gently, just as much as we laugh together,
零れる涙さえ今
Even spilling tears now,
ほら輝かせ明日へ運ぶから
Look, let it shine and carry it toward tomorrow.
君の隣へ 僕たちは世界を超えて行く
By your side, we go beyond the world.
迎えに行くよ まだ見えない明日も
We're coming to greet tomorrow, still unseen,
キラメキに変えてきっと
Turning it into glitter, surely,
僕たちが未来へと連れて行くから ！
Because we will take you to the future!
背伸びしては手を伸ばす 憧れの
Straightening our backs, reaching out our hands,
行き先示す星になろう
Let's become the star that shows the destination.
つまずくその度に手を差し伸べ合えたら
If we reach out our hands to each other every time we stumble,
すぐに届はずさ
It will surely reach us soon.
そっと踏み出した小さな勇気が
Let's connect the small courage we softly stepped out with
もう消えないように繋げよう
So it never fades away.
不安も愛情も大切に抱きしめて
Cherishing both anxiety and love,
共に 行く よ ！ 目 を 合わせ て
Let's go together! Looking into each other's eyes,
3 . 2 . 1 ！ 晴れ渡る希望へ飛び出せるよ ！
3, 2, 1! We can fly out to the clear, spreading hope!
突き抜けていく 僕たちの透き通る決意は
Our clear resolve breaking through
まだまだ止められないよ ！
Still cannot be stopped!
いつの間にか見つけていた遠い夢
A distant dream I found before I knew it
一人じゃ見えなかった景色
Scenery that could not be seen alone
波打つ風の音と加速していく想いに
To the sound of the rippling wind and the accelerating feelings,
戸惑いを覚えた
I felt bewildered.
ずっと追いかけた理想の姿は
The ideal figure I chased for so long
まだ届かなくて遠いけど
is still out of reach, but
きっとこの瞬間をかけがえないみんなで共に行くよ！
I'm sure this moment is irreplaceable, so let's go together!
手を繋いで
Hold hands,
3.2.1！
3, 2, 1!
輝き宿して 夢の場所へ！
Shine bright, to the place of dreams!
駆け抜けていく僕たちの青春の光は
The light of our youth running through
誰にも止められないよ！
can never be stopped by anyone!
笑い合う分だけ優しく零れる涙さえ
Even the tears that spill so gently
笑い合う分だけ優しい零れる涙さえ
just because we laugh together,
今ほら輝かせ明日へ運ぶから
Now, look, let them shine and carry us to tomorrow!
君の隣へ 僕たちは世界を超えて行く
By your side, we'll go beyond the world,
迎えに行くよ まだ見えない明日も
to welcome a future we haven't seen yet,
キラメキに変えて きっと僕たちが未来へと連れて行くから！
turning it all into a sparkling glitter,
僕たちが未来へと連れて行くから！
leading you into the future!
あすいろClearSky
Asuiro ClearSky
背伸びしては手を伸ばす憧れの
Reaching out with our backs stretched high,
行き先示す星になろう
let's become the stars that show the way.
つまずくその度に手を差し伸べ合えたら
Whenever we stumble, if we reach out to each other,
すぐに届くはずさ
we'll surely reach it in no time.
そっと踏み出した小さな勇気がもう消えないように繋ごう
Let's connect this small, courageous first step so it never fades,
不安も愛しさも大切に抱きしめて
holding both our anxieties and love close to our hearts.
共に行くよ！
Let's go together!
目を合わせて！
Match your eyes!
3.2.1！
3, 2, 1!
晴れ渡る希望へ飛び出せるよ！
Jump out into clear, boundless hope!
突き抜けていく僕たちの透き通る決意は
The transparent determination of our running through
誰にも止められないよ！
can never be stopped by anyone!
ありきたりな今日こそトキメキに変えて
Turning ordinary today into something thrilling,
もっと僕たちがいつでも背中押すから！
we will always be there to push you forward!
ずっと一人で描いていたキャンパスが
The canvas we used to draw on all alone
いつからかコライトになってまた少しずつ
has somehow become a colorful collage,
芽生える大好きを紡ぎ
sprouting new things we love,
どこまでも高くあすいろの空へ
soaring high up into the Asuiro sky!
駆け抜けていく僕たちの青春の光は
The light of our youth running through
誰にも止められないよ！
can never be stopped by anyone!
笑い合う分だけ優しく零れる涙さえ
Even the tears that spill so gently
笑い合う分だけ優しい零れる涙さえ
just because we laugh together,
今ほら輝かせ明日へ運ぶから
Now, look, let them shine and carry us to tomorrow!
君の隣へ 僕たちは世界を超えて行く
By your side, we'll go beyond the world,
迎えに行くよ まだ見えない明日も
to welcome a future we haven't seen yet,
キラメキに変えて きっと僕たちが未来へと…
turning it all into a sparkling glitter,
果ての無い未来へと連れて行くから！
leading you into the endless future!
地平線を水平線にしたら…
If the horizon was made horizontal...
ら・Sea ら・Sea ら・Sea・Sea・Sea！
La-Sea, La-Sea, La-Sea-Sea-Sea!
WAHHH！！！
WAHHH!!!
Sing! Shock! Sing! Shock! Sing! Shock! Sing! Shock!
波浪でみんなに HELLO, HELLO
HELLO, HELLO, everyone, HELLO, HELLO!
湧水 深海 Swing & Sweet
Tidal Wave, Deep Sea, Swing & Sweet!
ふっふー！
Fuu-fuu!
富い♡名誉♡清らかな称号♡4人でかっさらっちゃうぞ
Rich! Famous! Pure titles! Four people taking over!
さーさーさーさーさー！
Sa-sa-sa-sa-sa!
地球を侵略 TAKODA'CH急増！
Invading the earth with TAKODA'CH-enlargement!
いないいないーないないー
I-nai-i-nai-i-nai-i-nai-i-nai-!
えっこれで海賊本職化!?脱コスプレってことじゃん!!
Wait, this means pirate world domination?! And they're just cosplay costumes?!
キミたちも本物の味知りたいのか？
Do you guys also want to know the true taste of the sea?
Shrimp と salmon サメぜんぶ食べます
Shrimp, and salmon, we'll eat every single one!
(eat shrimp... we eat every single shrimp on the earth... oh, mic's on!)
全人未踏の
Zenjin mitou no...
母なる海へと
To the mother ocean...
水に落とされて…最高のDeep blue
into the deepest deep blue.
私(あてし)達の海へご招待
Invitation to the sea of (our) dreams!
(Our showtime!!)
(1) Depart the harbor
(2) Launch our marine-jet
(3) Start a shark-venture
(4) And TAKO-over the world with sea!
Here we go / いっせーの せーのっ
Here we go / Isse-no-sei!
おーしゃん おーしゃん Lovely ocean
O-shan O-shan Lovely ocean!
導いた新世界
Illuminating the newly revealed world,
青い星をウルトラマリンに染めて
dyeing the blue star in ultramarine!
おーしゃん おーしゃん Epic ocean
O-shan O-shan Epic ocean!
陸海全部かいかいかい！
Land and sea completely kai-kai-kai!
AQUA満杯 Bluest Planetへ進め
AQUA-filled Bluest Planet, full speed ahead!
ヨーソロー！ヨーソロー！
Yo-ho-ro! Yo-ho-ro!
この星を一つにしたら…
If this star was made a single ocean...
ら・Sea ら・Sea ら・Sea・Sea・Sea！
La-Sea, La-Sea, La-Sea-Sea-Sea!
WAHHH！！！
WAHHH!!!
行くぞー 騒げ騒げ こいやー！
Let's go, come on, let's get excited!
おー！みんな盛り上がってるかー！
Come on everyone, are you getting hyped up?!
りゅーーっときてきゅーーっ！！！
Ryuu-to-kite-kyuu-!
大地も大海も巻き込んで大混乱～！？
Pulling even the earth and vast seas into a huge uproar?!
(WE ARE UMISEA!! UMISEA.JP!!)
ぎゅーっとしてちゅーっとしてりゅーときてきゅーっ！！！
Gyuu-to shite chuo shite ryuu-to kite kyuu-!
ぱっぱっぱやっぱっぱっしぴっく
Pa-pa-pa-ya pa-pa-pa-shippiku!
ぱっぱっぱやっぱっぱっパラダイス
Pa-pa-pa-ya pa-pa-pa-paradise!
ぱや ぱやぱやぱや！
Pa-ya-pa-ya-pa-ya-!
荒くれ海に 漫食船
Rough sea, pirate ship,
大波 小波で 水の中(あーやー！)
big waves, small waves, inside the water (Ah-ya-!)
なんやかんやで サメとタコ
Somehow or other, sharks and octopuses
どっかにさらわれて 行方不明
kidnapped and missing in action!
りゅーーっときてきゅーーっ!!!
Ryuu--tto kite kyuu--tto!!!
じゃあ冒険しようよ (いぇーい)
Now then, let's go on an adventure! (Yay!)
なんくるたんけんだ (いぇーい)
It's a whatever-will-be adventure! (Yay!)
遭難しても すぐ助かるから ❤️
Even if we get lost, we'll be saved right away ❤️
(ぱくぱくぱく♪)
(Nom nom nom♪)
クルーの皆さん 宝物 探検 準備はいい~~??
Crew members, are you ready to hunt for treasure~~??
1! セクシー・船長
1! Sexy Captain!
2! 清楚・メイド
2! Seiso Maid!
3! “掃除屋”・ジャテ
3! "Cleaner" Shacha!
ポージィ・セッチュウ
Pose & Compromise!
あくまりさかまた おーおーしゃん
Aqua, Marine, Shakamata, Ocean!
りゅーーっときてきゅーーっ!!! (きゅーーっ!!!)
Ryuu--tto kite kyuu--tto!!! (Kyuu--tto!!!)
アクア的神様 深海は銀河のサブマリン
Aqua's divine mystery, the deep sea is a galactic submarine!
クロ潮のブラックホールへ だいぶつ
Diving into the Black Hole of the Kuroshio current!
りゅーーっときてきゅーーっ!!! (きゅーーっ!!!)
Ryuu--tto kite kyuu--tto!!! (Kyuu--tto!!!)
楽園アドベンチャー われわれトレジャーハンター
Paradise adventure, we are treasure hunters!
難解な地図の謎も (理解理解!)
Even the riddle of the cryptic map (Understood!)
ポンポンぽんさくっても (いただきまーす)
Plundering it away (It's-a time to eat!)
曖昧な航海図で (ヨーソロー!)
With a vague nautical chart (Ahoy!)
全力出力して
Putting in all our might,
(WE ARE UMISEA!! UMISEA JP!!)
ぎゅっしてちゅっしてりゅーときてきゅー!!!
Hug me, kiss me, ryuu--tto kite kyuu--tto!!!
はーい、ということで
Hi there! So,
クライマックスストーリーライブ特別コラボ、UMISEAとUMISEA JPによるUMISEAメドレーでしたー! いえーい!
this was the UMISEA Medley by UMISEA and UMISEA JP for the Climax Story Live special collab! Yay!
みんなね、もうグラもイナもニノちゃんも登場で盛り上がってると思いますが、ま、順番にね、自己紹介していきましょう。
I'm sure everyone's hyped with Gura, Ina, and Nino-chan's appearance, so let's introduce ourselves in order!
まずね、じゃあ船長からいきます!
First up, let's start with the Captain!
はーい！ ホロライブ3期生、宝鐘海賊団船長の宝鐘マリンです！ 君たちぇ楽しんでるかー！
Hi! I'm Houshou Marine, Captain of the Houshou Pirates, 3rd generation of Hololive! Are you guys having fun?!
いえーい!
Yay!
はい、次あくたんどうぞ!
Next is Akutan, go ahead!
はい！ 皆さんどうもこんにちはー！
Hi! Hello everyone!
ホロライブ2期生、港あくあです! こんにちはー!
I'm Minato Aqua, 2nd generation of Hololive! Hello!
いえーい!
Yay!
次！ ぱっくぱくぱく！ 秘密結社holoXの掃除要員！ 沙花叉クロヱです！ 君たち見えてるかー！
Next! Paku paku paku! Secret Society holoX's cleanup crew! Shachamata Chloe! Can you guys see us?!
いえーい!
Yay!
はーい、おはようこんにちはこんばんは、ホロライブEnglish・Mythの二ノ瀬いなすです、よろしくお願いします！
Hi, good morning, afternoon, evening, I'm Ninomae Ina'nis from Hololive English Myth, nice to meet you!
いえーい!
Yay!
はろー、どうも、サメです！ホロライブEnglish・Mythのガウル・グラです！
Hello, hello, it's shark! I'm Gawr Gura from Hololive English Myth!
はい、じゃあなんでこの5人なのっていう人もいると思うんで、船長が説明してあげようかな。
So, some of you might be wondering why it's these 5 people, so the Captain will explain it to you.
確かにね、ENの2人がゲストで来てくれたの、マジびっくりしてる人もいるかもね。ね？ さっき歌ったのはですね、UMISEAメドレーということでね、君たち覚えてるかな？
That's true, some of you might be genuinely surprised that the two EN members came as guests. Right? What we just sang was the UMISEA Medley, do you guys remember?
前半の曲は去年の夏にリリースされた新曲「地球系説得音頭」！
The first half song was the new song released last summer, "Chikyuu-kei Settoku Ondo"!
やっぱ夏といえばね、私たちUMISEAでしょっていうことでね、ええ。
After all, when it comes to summer, it's us UMISEA, right? So, yeah.
ENの2人にも特別ゲストとして出演しても…しゅ、しゅーとさんとわきだしよ。
We also had the two EN members appear as special guests... Shuu-to-san and wakidashi yo.
ねえ！
Right?!
あー、こちらこそ誘ってくれてありがとうございます！
Ah, thank you so much for inviting me!
いや、去年のテンションも高かったと思ったんですが、今年はライブでみんなのダンスもあり、なんかレベルアップした感じですね。
I thought last year's tension was already high, but this year everyone was dancing live, and it feels like it leveled up somehow.
私も嬉しいです!
I'm happy too!
かわいい！ まり先輩、まり先輩ありがとうございます！
Cute! Mari-senpai, Mari-senpai, thank you very much!
そして、Welcome、Chloe！もっとぐら先輩！
And welcome, Chloe! And more Gura-senpai!
トキミの家族になりましたね!
We became the Tokimi family!
そして、この大きいステージで、えー得られた、とどーくUMISEAの数からも1年が経ったことが信じられない。Happy Birthday to UMISEA！この音楽は世界中の全ての海岸まで届くように。
And being able to receive this on such a big stage, I can't believe a year has passed since UMISEA's number. Happy Birthday to UMISEA! May this music reach every coast around the world.
グッドジャパニーズ。
Good Japanese.
ということでね、えー後半歌った曲、「りゅーーっときてきゅーーっ」は29日0時より配信がスタートしております!
So, the song we sang in the second half, "Ryuu--tto kite kyuu--tto", started distribution from midnight on the 29th!
みんな聞いてくれたかな？
Did everyone listen to it?
りゅーーっときてきゅーーからは、沙花叉も仲間に加わっております!
From "Ryuu--tto kite kyuu", Shakamata has also joined as a friend!
沙花叉、どうでしたか?
Shakamata, how was it?
沙花叉が初参戦した「りゅーーっときてきゅーー」はセリフパートがめちゃ早口だったので、噛みまくって大変でした!
"Ryuu--tto kite kyuu", which Shakamata participated in for the first time, had a super fast-paced spoken part, so I tripped over my words and it was tough!
でも、オーシャンの時に好きだった先輩たちのおじゃわちゃしたかけ合いを、沙花叉も一緒にできて楽しかったです!
But it was fun being able to join in with the lively banter of the seniors I liked during Ocean!
はい、じゃあ沙花叉も加わったことで5人になりましたね。
Right, so with Shakamata joining, we're 5 people now.
ということで、念願のポーズができますと!
So, we can do our long-awaited pose!
じゃあみんな、配置についてください! グライナ、Ready to pose! Let's go!
So everyone, take your positions! Gura, Ina, Ready to pose! Let's go!
あ、ちょっとぐら、センターだ、ぐらセンター。
Ah, wait, Gura's center, Gura's center.
ぐらセンターで、あ、あ、ちょっと、あた、あ、右左、待って
Gura center, and, ah, wait, right and left, wait—
ちょっと、で、番号のこうちゃん？ え、これがあれ？ここ？
Wait, numbering like this? Eh, is this that? Here?
じゃあ！人手、人手のポーズ。
Now then! Hitode, the starfish pose.
いなう、いなう、いなう
Inao, Inao, Inao!
さあ！はい、さて、そろそろ時間となってきましたので、次の曲に行きましょうか。
Now! Right, well, it's about time, so shall we move on to the next song?
はい、えー、ぐら、いなにさん、今日は本当に駆けつけてくれてありがとうございます。
Yes, um, Gura, Ina-nisan, thank you so much for rushing over today.
イエーイ！楽しかった！
Yay! It was so fun!
楽しかったです！ありがとうございます！
It was fun! Thank you so much!
はい、これからはね、この5人で毎年夏と海を盛り上げていければと思いますからね。
Yes, from now on, I hope we can liven up summer and the ocean with these five every year.
じゃ、元気よく次の曲フリしましょうか。
Well, let's cheerfully introduce the next song.
じゃ、せーので、いきますか！
Well, on three, shall we go?
じゃ、ぐら、ぐら行ってみよっか。
Well, Gura, shall Gura try going?
わかりました！それでは集大成の曲は…！
Understood! Then the culmination song is...
こっちだー！
Over here!
そうさ ずっと！ 僕らの奇跡が途切れないように歌うんだ
That's right! We'll keep singing so our miracle never fades!
もっと 高高く！ 大きな声で聞こえたかい？何かが始まるサイン
Even higher! With a loud voice. Did you hear it? The sign that something is beginning.
集まった気づけば和音を奏でた
We gathered, and before we knew it, we were playing a chord.
夢に見るだけじゃもう足りないでしょ？
Just dreaming isn't enough anymore, right?
キミを待っている世界があるよ 楽しい予感にほら飛び乗っちゃえばいい
There's a world waiting for you. Come on, just jump into the joyful premonition!
トキメキは止められないから走ろう！
We can't stop this excitement, so let's run!
連れて行くよ！光の真ん中 夢の先へ
I'll take you! To the center of the light, beyond our dreams.
羽ばたける勇気はキミの願い 皆で繋いだこの奇跡が
The courage to spread our wings is your wish, and this miracle we wove together...
途切れないように歌うんだ もっと高く！大きな声で
We'll keep singing so it never fades, higher and higher with a loud voice!
答えとか理屈に惑わされても
Even if we're confused by answers or logic,
さまよっても戻って来られる場所があったんだ
even if we wander, there was a place we could return to.
地図にない道ゆく僕らの旅 願いだけが道標だよ
Our journey takes paths not on any map, where our wishes are our only signposts.
夢の色が変わっても変わらないメロディ キミのために僕らのために歌おう！
Even if the color of our dreams changes, this melody remains the same. Let's sing it for you, for us!
そうさきっと！僕らの奇跡は終わらないよ 涙さえキッかけに変えていこう
That's right, for sure! Our miracle won't end. Let's turn even our tears into a catalyst!
信じてくれる仲間と一緒に どこへだって飛び出していこう
Together with friends who believe in us, let's burst out anywhere!
もっと遠く！空を超えて
Further away! Beyond the skies.
未来の僕らにまだ見ぬキミに伝えたいことたくさんあるんだ
There's so much I want to tell our future selves and the yet-unseen you.
迎えたイマは当たり前なんかじゃない 翼を広げさあ今飛ぼう！
The present we've welcomed isn't just something to take for granted. Spread your wings and let's fly now!
take my hand !
Take my hand!
連れて行くよ！光の真ん中 夢の先へ
I'll take you! To the center of the light, beyond our dreams.
羽ばたける勇気はキミの願い 皆で繋いだこの奇跡が
The courage to spread our wings is your wish, and this miracle we wove together...
途切れないように歌うんだ もっと高く！大きな声で
We'll keep singing so it never fades, higher and higher with a loud voice!
僕らの未来彩ってどこまでも響け！ prism melody
Color our future and echo everywhere! Prism Melody!
そうさ君と僕らの奇跡は終わらないよ
That's right, our miracle with you will never end!
涙さえきっかけに変えていこう 信じてくれる仲間と一緒に
Let's turn even our tears into a catalyst, together with friends who believe in us!
どこへだって飛び出していこう もっと遠く空を越えて
Let's burst out anywhere, further away across the sky!
翼を広げさあ今飛ぼう！光の真ん中夢の先へ
Spread your wings and let's fly now, to the center of the light beyond our dreams!
未来の僕らにまだ見ぬキミに伝えたいことたくさんあるんだ
There's so much I want to tell our future selves and the yet-unseen you.
迎えたイマは当たり前なんかじゃない 翼を広げさあ今飛ぼう！
The present we've welcomed isn't just something to take for granted. Spread your wings and let's fly now!
連れて行くよ！光の真ん中 夢の先へ
I'll take you! To the center of the light, beyond our dreams.
羽ばたける勇気はキミの願い 皆で繋いだこの奇跡が
The courage to spread our wings is your wish, and this miracle we wove together...
途切れないように歌うんだ もっと高く！大きな声で
We'll keep singing so it never fades, higher and higher with a loud voice!
皆で繋いだこの奇跡が途切れないように歌うんだもっと高く！大きな声で
We'll keep singing so this miracle we wove together never fades, higher and higher with a loud voice!
暗闇の未来いろどって
Coloring the dark future,
どこまでも響け リズム メロディ
resound everywhere, rhythm melody!
ちょっとそこ行く 南の皆様よ
Hey you folks over there, everyone from the south!
僕らと一緒に 踊らない？
Won't you dance along with us?
さあ お手を拝借
Now, lend us your hands!
ポポン ガポン はい！
Popon gapon, hey!
ちょうちん灯れば 笑顔集どぅ
When paper lanterns light up, smiles gather.
ホロメン音頭 (あーよいしょ)
Horomen Ondo (Ah, yoisho!)
うちわ わたあめ かき氷 だね
Paper fans, cotton candy, and shaved ice.
バーリラ バーリラ ワンコも踊る (そーれ)
Barira barira, even doggies dance (Sore!)
みんな揃って どどんがどどん
Everyone gathering, dodon ga dodon,
まつり囃子だ どどんがどどん
Festival music playing, dodon ga dodon!
よいしょ あーどっこい
Yoisho! Ah, dokkoi!
あかね くなし わかなえ しおん
Akane, Kunashi, Wakanae, Shion...
ホロメン音頭 (あーよいしょ)
Horomen Ondo (Ah, yoisho!)
浴衣 あざやか 花吹雪 だね
Vibrant yukatas and a flurry of flower petals.
バーリラ バーリラ 金魚も踊る (そーれ)
Barira barira, even goldfish dance (Sore!)
みんな揃って どどんがどどん
Everyone gathering, dodon ga dodon,
まつり囃子だ どどんがどどん
Festival music playing, dodon ga dodon!
ホロメンを集めて囃し 保護者かな
Gathering Holomembers and cheering them on, like a guardian?
推しのことだね 満ちる幸せ
It's about my oshi, filling me with happiness.
「さぁさぁ皆さん、音頭を踊れば温度が上がる！」
"Come on everyone, dancing the ondo raises the temperature!"
「赤ん坊から閑かん坊まで、誰でもいらっしゃれ～！」
"From babies to the elderly, everyone is welcome!"
あぁ、こまけぇこたぁいいんだよ
Ah, the details don't matter!
今宵の祭 シャル・ウィ・ダンス
Tonight's festival, Shall We Dance?
踊り踊らば はっぴっぴー
When we dance and dance, we're happy-happy!
ヨヨイ宵の口 西明かり遠か
Evening begins, the western twilight is far away.
ホロメン音頭 (あーよいしょ)
Horomen Ondo (Ah, yoisho!)
光りざめく 天の川 だね
Sparkling Milky Way.
バーリラ バーリラ ばあばも踊る (そーれ)
Barira barira, even grannies dance (Sore!)
みんな揃って どどんがどどん
Everyone gathering, dodon ga dodon,
まつり囃子だ どどんがどどん
Festival music playing, dodon ga dodon!
よいしょ はーどっこい
Yoisho! Ha, dokkoi!
目引き袖引き ご一緒いかが
Pulling eyes and sleeves, won't you join us?
ホロメン音頭 (あーよいしょ)
Horomen Ondo (Ah, yoisho!)
花火 ヒュルリラ 夏の夜 だね
Fireworks whistling, it's a summer night.
バーリラ バーリラ わらべも踊る (そーれ)
Barira barira, even children dance (Sore!)
みんな揃って どどんがどどん
Everyone gathering, dodon ga dodon,
まつり囃子だ どどんがどどん
Festival music playing, dodon ga dodon!
(はぁ～てぇてぇなぁ！てぇてぇなぁ！両手を合わせ てぇてぇなぁ！)
(Ha~ precious! Precious! Put your hands together, precious!)
(てぇてぇなぁ！てぇてぇなぁ！両手を合わせ てぇてぇなぁ！)
(Precious! Precious! Put your hands together, precious!)
ひょいと見上げりゃ 望月にこり
Glance up and see the smiling harvest moon.
ホロメン音頭 (あーよいしょ)
Horomen Ondo (Ah, yoisho!)
少し切ない 夢心地 だね
A slightly bittersweet dreamlike feeling.
バーリラ バーリラ 夜っぴて踊る (そーれ)
Barira barira, dancing all through the night (Sore!)
みんな揃って どどんがどどん
Everyone gathering, dodon ga dodon,
まつり囃子だ どどんがどどん
Festival music playing, dodon ga dodon!
はい、ということで お祭りでしたー！
Alright, and that concludes our festival!
さあさあさあさあ、早速でまずは自己紹介からしていきたいと思います！
Now then, let's start with self-introductions!
一番、すばるです！おねがいします！そして！
First, it's Subaru! Nice to meet you! And—
ホロライブゲーマーズ、戌神ころね！や、指々！よろしくおねがいします！
Hololive Gamers, Inugami Korone! Y-, finger-finger! Nice to meet you!
そしてからの…
And then...
注目せよ！我が輩の名前は…ラプラス・ダークネスだ。
Pay attention! My name is... La+ Darkness.
あ、続いては？
Ah, next is?
おい！一番、ゆびゆび！注目せよ！えー、こよ…あ、ホロライブ４期の常闇トワでーす！
Hey! First, finger-finger! Pay attention! Uh, Koyo... Ah, I'm Hololive 4th Gen's Tokoyami Towa!
ということでですね、以上のメンバーでホロライブ夏祭り2022の新曲「ホロメン音頭」をお送りしました！
So, with these members, we delivered the new song "Holomen Ondo" for Hololive Summer 2022!
いやー、ていうか今までなかったそういう曲だったから、すごい新鮮だったよね。
Man, since we didn't have a song quite like this before, it felt really fresh.
しかも、なんとこのフ、あ、この曲を公式ショップで買うと、なんと！お祭りで使えるんだぞ、みんなの！
Moreover, if you buy this song at the official shop, guess what! You can use it at the festival, everyone!
やったー！
Yay!
ラプちゃん読めたね！読めたね！
Lap-chan, you read it! You read it!
まあね、今年はもうだから、来年とかでも使ってもらえたらなと思います！
Well, since it's already this year, I hope people will use it next year and beyond!
はい、ということでですね、詳しくはホロライブ夏祭り2022の公式ショップから確認してみてください！お願いします！
Yes, so please check the official Hololive Summer 2022 shop for details! Please do!
お、で、せっかくだから、なんと！浴衣なのだ！
Oh, and since we're wearing yukatas!
せっかくだから、スクショをとろう！せーの！
Let's take a screenshot! Ready, set!
かっこいいの。かっこいいの。
A cool one. A cool one.
それでは、じゃあ、エスワイダン、決めていきます！
Now then, let's strike an "EsuwAIDan" pose!
せーの、注目せよ！エスワイダン！
Ready, set, pay attention! EsuwAIDan!
はい、ということでですね、えー、なんとですね、ちょっと早いんですけど、次がね、最後の曲みたいで！
Yes, so, um, surprisingly, although it's a bit early, it looks like the next song is the last one!
ま、でもね、ちょっと名残惜しいんですけど、で、も最後はやっぱりね、あのホロライブ夏祭り2022の新曲３つ目の新曲で終わりみたいですよ！
Well, it's a bit bittersweet, but it seems the final song will be the third new song of Hololive Summer 2022!
ちなみに、この曲が終わった後、みなさん帰らないでください！
By the way, after this song finishes, everyone, please don't leave!
なんか、すごいサプライズが待ってるみたいですね！
It seems like an amazing surprise is waiting for us!
はい、というわけで、みなさん気になってると思うので、早速次の曲にいっちゃいましょう！
Yes, so since I think everyone's curious, let's jump right into the next song!
クライマックスストーリーライブのトリを飾る曲は！…せーの、こちら！
The song closing out the climax story live is— Ready, set, here it is!
夏が何度巡り来ても
No matter how many summers come around,
忘れないでいたい
I want to never forget them.
少し寂しいと思ったんだ
I thought it was a little lonely,
浴衣の袖を揺らす
swaying the sleeves of my yukata.
「風が涼しいね」なんて言った
As you said, "The breeze is cool,"
君の表情見つけたせいかな
was it because I caught sight of your expression?
日が暮れるまではしゃいで笑ってるの
Laughing and playing until the sun goes down,
オレンジが映ったシルエット
an orange-tinted silhouette.
蝉の歌声や 波の騒ぎが
Cicadas' song and the roar of the waves
遠くなっていったって きっと思い出せる
faded into the distance, but I'm sure I'll remember.
祭りの夜の空を見ると
When I look up at the festival night sky,
まるで思い出の数だけ
it's as if the number of memories
色が光っているみたいだね
are shining in different colors.
一つ一つ綺麗に 咲いて咲いて行くよ
Blooming, blooming, one by one, so beautifully.
新しい浴衣着替えて
Changing into a new yukata,
「どうかな？」って見せ合ったり
"How do I look?" you asked with a spin.
気温のせいにしちゃって
Blaming it on the temperature,
熱い気持ちで未来を語ったり
Talking about the future with such hot feelings.
( memories )
どんなことでも冒険みたいになる
Making any adventure feel like a grand journey,
期待値が上がってしまうシーズン
A season where expectations only rise.
当たり前の日も特別ってこと
Even everyday days are something special—
この瞬間、この一瞬だって
In this very moment, this very instant.
だって思わせる
That's what I find myself thinking.
賑わう人で混み合うほど
So crowded with people hustling about,
何故だか楽しい気分だね
Why does it feel so strangely fun?
動画の窓のような屋台
Like looking through the windows of a movie,
一つ一つ覗いて
Peering into each and every one.
一緒に一緒に歩こう
Let's walk together, side by side.
振り返っても
Even if I look back,
ほんのちょっとも
Just for a tiny second,
トリミング出来ないようなシーンばっかり
It's full of scenes I just can't trim out.
過ぎ去ってしてしまう前に もう一度だけ
Before it slips away, just one more time,
みんなといたい
I want to be with everyone.
想い出たちを彩るように
As if to color our memories,
夜空に咲いた花火が
The fireworks blooming in the night sky
色鮮やかに輝いてた
Were shining so brilliantly and bright.
ずっと…一緒にいたいよ
I want to stay together... forever.
来年もまたこんな風に 笑い合いたいって思うから
Hoping we can laugh together just like this next year too,
線香花火に願うんだ
I make a wish upon a sparkler:
「ずっと ずっと 続いて」
"Please, let this last and last."
きっと きっと 叶う
I'm sure, I'm sure it will come true.
Parade, Parade, Parade! 輝くんだよ
Parade, Parade, Parade! Let's make it shine.
呼び合う声を 合図に
Using our calling voices as the cue.
Parade, Parade, Parade! 探しにゆく
Parade, Parade, Parade! Let's go search.
スタートは 何度だって
How many times was our start?
ただ 独り言を呟いた
Just talking to ourselves,
ただ 始まりりたくて走った
Just running because we wanted it to begin.
遠く 暗がりでに灯った
Far away, a light flickered in the darkness.
それは 眩し過ぎた名前
That was a name too dazzling,
それは 優し過ぎる思い出もきっと
That was a memory too kind.
近付けと 手を伸ばした
Reaching out our hands to get closer,
思いがけず 結び合った
Unexpectedly, we became intertwined.
ほら 今 迷子は “僕等” になった
Look, now the strays have become "us."
Parade, Parade, Parade! 輝くんだよ
Parade, Parade, Parade! Let's make it shine.
悔しさも 愛しさも 連れておいでよ
Bring your regrets and your love along with you.
風、夢、羽 飛び立てるさ
Wind, dreams, and feathers take flight.
ささやかな祈りは 光 終わり無い 兆し
A modest prayer is a light that never stops growing.
君を見つけたこと 胸を張れるよ
Finding you lets me hold my head high.
ここから これから our bright parade, parade!
From here and now, our bright parade!
まだ 頼りない予感を 歌おう
Singing of yet uncertain premonitions,
恥ずかしかくなんかないないよ
There's nothing to be embarrassed about.
誰も解けない イマジナリー
An imaginary world nobody can solve.
いつか また逢える おまじない
A spell to meet again someday.
あの日ゼロに始まった ストーリー
A story that started at zero that day.
数え切れない 言の葉
Countless leaves of words,
数えられるような 想いじゃないさ
Not feelings that can be simply counted.
ほら 今 “僕等” を一つと呼ぼう
Look, now let's call "us" a single whole.
Parade, Parade, Parade! 美しいんだよ
Parade, Parade, Parade! It's so beautiful.
許し合える 刹那 夜は きらめく
The fleeting night where we forgive each other sparkles.
雨、晴れ、カレイド またとない空
Rain, shine, or kaleidoscope, a sky unlike any other.
超えてく世界に見せてあげる
I'll show it to the world as we push past!
世界に見せてあげる
I'll show it to the world!
アクセスしてみたい
I want to try accessing it,
後悔なんてさせない
and I won't let you regret it.
それぞれ違ったココロで走れ go
Run with our own different hearts, go!
走れ go
Run, go!